<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unity on My journey in IGD301</title>
    <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/tags/unity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unity on My journey in IGD301</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 12:48:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/tags/unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementation</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 12:48:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/implementation/</guid>
      <description>The concept I implemented what I explained in the Elevator Pitch and added a few things that I will explain in more details.&#xA;Implementation Selection For the Selection, I took a ray from the player to the controller and multiplied it to have the virtual hand position. To select an object, you press the index trigger.&#xA;I had to make two choices:&#xA;Where on the player would be the origin ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roll a Ball VR</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/rollaballvr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 13:44:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/rollaballvr/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Switching to PC I am usually working on a MacBook Air, so I followed the instruction of the TD up to the point where I had to download the Oculus application, which do not exist for MacOS&amp;hellip;&#xA;So I had to redo all of the configuration on my fix PC which I did not use for a while, installing Unity, visual studio, etc. Fortunatelly, I just had to follow the same steps as for my Mac installation and it was quick enough as I already knew how to do it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roll A Ball Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/rollaball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:22:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/rollaball/</guid>
      <description>Setup I followed the Unity tutorial named Roll a Ball. It was a simple Unity project to understand the basics of making a game.&#xA;Most of the setup is basic, most of the work is already done for you, you just need to open a template. The only issue is that I was not able to create a URP (Univesal Render Pipeline) project because my version of Unity is too old, so I created a more basic 3D poject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B: Unity setup</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/b_unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 14:48:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/b_unity/</guid>
      <description>Setup of Unity I already had Unity installed from another course. Because I did not want to use too much space, I decided to stay on the same version and just add the necessary modules for this course:&#xA;Once the modules installed, I created a new 3D project. The first thing i did was changing the background color while on play mode because I made too much unsaved changes on my previous project (every modifiations made while in project mode are discarded).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
