<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab on My journey in IGD301</title>
    <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/tags/lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lab on My journey in IGD301</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 12:48:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/tags/lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementation</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 12:48:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/implementation/</guid>
      <description>The concept I implemented what I explained in the Elevator Pitch and added a few things that I will explain in more details.&#xA;Implementation Selection For the Selection, I took a ray from the player to the controller and multiplied it to have the virtual hand position. To select an object, you press the index trigger.&#xA;I had to make two choices:&#xA;Where on the player would be the origin ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elevator Pitch</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/elevatorpitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 12:13:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/elevatorpitch/</guid>
      <description>Doctor Octopus I decided to immplement the method where have extendable arm. There is two differents parts to implement: one being the movement, the other being the selection. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how I intent on implementing, both of them.&#xA;Selection The idea behid the selection is that you have a virtual double of your arm that is longer than your original arm, but but points in the same direction.&#xA;To implement this, I will look at the vector from the head to the controller and multiply it by some amount to have the position of the virtual hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Selection Pitch</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/3techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 15:41:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/3techniques/</guid>
      <description>Scalable Market Core idea You move and scale a supermarket around you.&#xA;This is inspired by the hologram map in avatar, except you can scale it as big as you want and make it go all arround you.&#xA;Manipulation You move in the scene by pinching with your hands as you would do on a tactile screen with your fingers. Then you move the supermarket arround you up to the point where the desired object is right in front of you, and here you just grab it</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roll a Ball VR</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/rollaballvr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 13:44:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/rollaballvr/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Switching to PC I am usually working on a MacBook Air, so I followed the instruction of the TD up to the point where I had to download the Oculus application, which do not exist for MacOS&amp;hellip;&#xA;So I had to redo all of the configuration on my fix PC which I did not use for a while, installing Unity, visual studio, etc. Fortunatelly, I just had to follow the same steps as for my Mac installation and it was quick enough as I already knew how to do it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B: Unity setup</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/b_unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 14:48:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/b_unity/</guid>
      <description>Setup of Unity I already had Unity installed from another course. Because I did not want to use too much space, I decided to stay on the same version and just add the necessary modules for this course:&#xA;Once the modules installed, I created a new 3D project. The first thing i did was changing the background color while on play mode because I made too much unsaved changes on my previous project (every modifiations made while in project mode are discarded).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A: Blog setup</title>
      <link>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/a_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 11:47:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rrulyx.github.io/HugoBlog/en/posts/a_hugo/</guid>
      <description>Quick Start For the blog, I followed the Quick start tutorial of HUGO.&#xA;I changed the theme for the theme for the Hermit-V2. Therefore, I had to make a little setup in the hugo.toml configuration file.&#xA;Deployment I deployed the site to GitHub by following the Host on GitHub Pages tutorial.&#xA;This is my first website !</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
